homeoffice.gov.uk 2013-03-27

# Terms and conditions | Home Office

**Terms and conditions of the Home Office website include: cookies, Crown copyright, links to other websites, links from other websites to the Home Office website, privacy policy and Data Protection Act 1998.**

### Cookies

[Read our cookie policy](http://www.homeoffice.gov.uk/cookies/) to see how we use cookies on our websites.

### © Crown copyright 2012

You may use and re-use the information featured on this website (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium, under the terms of the [open government licence](http://www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence "External link opens in a new window").

We encourage users to establish hypertext links to this website. See the terms and conditions of this below. 

Please send enquiries regarding the use and re-use of this information resource to [psi@nationalarchives.gsi.gov.uk](mailto:psi@nationalarchives.gsi.gov.uk).

### Third party copyright

Permission to reuse Crown copyright material does not extend to any material on the site that is the copyright of a third party. Permission to reuse such information would need to be obtained from the copyright holder concerned.

### Links to other websites

Please note that the Home Office takes no responsibility for the content of any of the external websites we link to from this website. 

### Links from other websites to the Home Office website

We encourage you to add links to the Home Office website, however please ensure you comply with the conditions below:

  * the link to us must not imply explicitly by description or implicitly by location of the link or logo on the page that the services/products/etc your organisation supplies are endorsed by the Home Office

  * if you use the Home Office logo it must be used unamended - it must not be edited

  * if you use the logo you must always include an alt tag

  * if the logo itself is used as a hyperlink, it must only link to the Home Office home page - [www.homeoffice.gov.uk](http://www.homeoffice.gov.uk/ "External link opens in a new window")

  * the link to the Home Office site must not load the page into frames - the page must load into the user's entire window 

### Privacy policy

The Home Office reserves the right to gather information relating to site usage. Any information gathered is primarily for internal use to allow us to refine and improve our customer service. Where disclosure of information to a third party is likely we will, where possible, endeavour to ensure that this is clearly indicated. This does not affect your statutory rights.

This site uses an online measuring package called SiteSat which uses cookies to identify repeat visits. Our site is also carrying banner advertising for government services which use cookies in order to avoid you seeing the same advertisements repeated over and over, and to allow us to gauge the number of people viewing a campaign or particular web page.

Cookies are pieces of data created when you visit a site, and contain a unique, anonymous number. They are stored in the cookie directory of your hard drive, and do not expire at the end of your session. Cookies used by the Home Office contain no personal information about the user, nor does our website elicit or store any information from users other than the Internet Protocol address of the computer used to access the site. Cookies on this site may safely be turned off by users without affecting how pages are displayed. 

### Data Protection Act 1998

The processing of personal data is governed by the Data Protection Act 1998, under which the Home Office is registered as a data controller. Any personal data you provide will be held securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.  We will use your personal data for the purpose(s) in relation to which you have provided it. We may however need to disclose personal data to a third party so that they can provide the service you have requested, or fulfil a Subject Access Request. 

We may additionally need to disclose information where there is a legitimate reason for disclosure (such as a court order) but we will ensure that we always comply with the Data Protection Act. Any information about you that we pass to a third party will be held securely by that party, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, and used only to provide services or information you have requested.

As a data subject you have the right to ask for a copy of personal data about you and to ask for inaccuracies to be corrected. Queries about Home Office compliance with the Data Protection Act should be addressed to:

Information Policy Team  
Information and Record Management Services  
4th Floor  
Seacole Building  
2 Marsham Street  
London  
SW1P 4DF
